# **Kevin Bernard**

### **HVAC/R Technician**

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Kevin-Bernard/43b73d390bde141b

Heating, Ventilation, Air Conditioning and Refrigeration Technician with a degree in Mechanical and Technology Engineer. Qualifications include 12 years' of military experience in Heating, Ventilating, Air Conditioning, and Refrigeration (HVAC/R) residential, commercial systems, combustion equipment, and industrial air compressor maintenance, supervising and project management. Creates and executes project work plans and revises as appropriate to meet changing needs and requirements. Effectively prepare for engagement reviews, quality assurance procedures and minimizing exposure and risk on projects to ensure project documents are complete, current, and stored appropriately.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

### WORK EXPERIENCE

### **HVAC/R Craftsman**

United States Air Force - Spangdahlem - August 2010 to January 2015

schedules and trains HVAC/R mechanics on the installation of mechanical and electrical controls for HVAC/R equipment

- Managed the installation, maintenance, and repair of 10 ton carrier chiller for a \$1.2B dollar Intelligence processing system
- Preventive Maintenance Supervisor- Inspects and ensures 100 percent operational capacity of all HVAC/R equipment items, and produces data trends to reduce waste
- Maintenance Training Manager Manages individual training records for 32 Civil Engineer personnel and conducts briefings on performance and provides timelines to uphold compliance standards
- Supervised installation of 10 ton carrier chiller for \$5M dollar Armed Forces Broadcasting Network equipment boosted morale for 7900+ deployed troops

### **HVAC/R Journeyman**

United States Air Force - May 2005 to August 2010

McGuire AFB, NJ

- Managed recurring maintenance and installs, and repairs for over 2,500 pieces of HVAC/R equipment and 70 medium and low-temperature refrigeration systems
- Interpreted drawings, blueprints, schematics, and sketches used to troubleshoot HVAC/R systems
- Tested electrical and pneumatic controls for proper calibration and operation used for control of temperatures, humidity, ventilating and exhaust systems

### **HVAC/R Mechanic**

United States Air Force - April 2003 to May 2005

Ramstein AFB, GE

- Complied with all EPA guidelines, applicable standards, policies, and procedures, including correct safety practice during recovery and repairs
- Installed, maintained, and serviced chilled water and direct expansion Air Conditioner systems up to 160 tons, warm air furnaces, heating and steam boilers up to 13 million British Thermal Units, ice machines, reachin and walk-in freezers, and fan coil units.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Science in Criminal Justice**

Allied American University 2014 to Present

# **Associates in Mechanical and Electrical Technology**

Community College of the Air Force - Maxwell, AL 2012 to 2013

# **SKILLS**

Pneumatic Controls, Direct Digital Controls, calibration, Schematics, Air Compressors, Critical Thinking, Soldering and Brazing, Troubleshooting, Motor Controllers, Safety, Installation, Repairs, Maintenance

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

# **EPA Universal Certificate**

April 2003 to Present

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

# 1. AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Leadership Training

Troubleshooting Schematics Civil Engineering Motor Controllers Calibration
Safety Pneumatic Systems Air Compressors
Direct Digital Controls 410A Certified Critical Thinking
Management Soldering & Brazing Heat Load Calculation Split Air Condition Systems